And welcome back to team PC and Team Mac as we come back together again for a quick video.
PC 팀과 Mac 팀에 다시 오신 걸 환영합니다 짧은 비디오를 위해 다시 뭉쳤네요
In this one, I'm just going to quickly walk through what you do.
이번에는 당신이 하는 일을 간단히 설명할게요
If Anaconda has given you problems, you're not able to get that to work and you want to fall back to
아나콘다가 문제가 된다면 get it을 할 수 없습니다. 그러면 간단한 virtualenv
the simpler virtualenv approach.
접근을 사용하세요.
This is a quicker, simpler approach.
이게 더 빠르고 간단해요
It's less guaranteed to be compatible.
양립이 보장되진 않아요 less
It's less heavyweight and powerful than the Anaconda environment, but it's perfectly okay.
아나콘다보다 무겁지도 않고 힘도 덜 세지만 그럭저럭 괜찮아요
And so by all means, use this if you would prefer.
그러니 원한다면 이걸 사용하세요
So I'm going to do it on my Mac.
제 Mac에서 할 거예요
But I'll point out when things are different for the PC and it's basically the same, although I'll
PC에 대해 다른 점은 기본적으로 같다는 거죠 비록 설명서가
say the the instructions begin where it says alternative setup instructions in the Readme on on the,
시작되는 곳은 다른 설정 설명서가 있는 곳이지만요 리뎀션에 있는 읽기에요
And one important difference between PC and Mac is that if you haven't, I imagine that that almost
PC와 Mac의 중요한 차이점 중 하나는 경험이 없다면 이 앱에 있는 거의 모든 사람이 자신의
everyone on this has has installed Python before on their PC.
PC에 파이썬을 설치해본 적이 있을 거라는 거죠
But if you haven't, then you will need to do that.
하지만 아직 안 했다면 그렇게 해야 해요
Python comes on Macs by default, but not on PCs, so I've got a link in here to go to the Python website.
파이썬 은 기본적으로 Macs로 나오지만 PC에서는 아닙니다 그래서 파이썬 웹사이트로 가는 링크를 걸어두었어요
When you go to the Python download website, you can choose to download the latest version of Python,
파이썬 을 다운로드 하실 때 최신 버전의 파이썬 을 다운로드할 수 있습니다 파이썬 3을 선택하는
but it might be better to choose Python 3.11.9, which is the latest version 3.11 to be compatible,
것이 더 나을 수도 있어요 11살요 9는 최신 버전 3이죠 호환 가능하도록요 그리고
and you can come down here and do a windows installer to install on windows.
여기로 와서 윈도우에 설치할 윈도우 설치자를 할 수 있어요
And if you don't have this version and if you have the time to install this version on windows, that
이 버전이 없고 Windows에 이 버전을 설치할 시간이 있다면
would be better.
그게 더 낫겠죠
Okay.
네
Once you have done that, then on a mac, bring up a terminal window on the PC.
그렇게 하고 나면 Mac에서 PC의 터미널 창을 띄워요
Bring up a normal PowerShell prompt, not the Anaconda prompt, just a regular prompt, and go into
아나콘다 프롬프트 말고 일반적인 PowerShell 프롬프트를 불러옵니다
the projects directory that we created earlier and then into the LM Engineering directory where the
아까 만든 프로젝트 디렉토리로 가서 프로젝트가 있는 LM 엔지니어링 디렉토리로
project sits.
가요
And now you do a simple command.
이제 간단한 명령을 하죠
Let's first just quickly check what version of Python we're running Python minus minus version.
먼저 파이썬 을 어떤 버전으로 실행하는지 빠르게 확인해 봅시다 파이썬 마이너스 버전이죠
And on my computer my default version is actually 3.12.3.
제 컴퓨터의 기본 버전은 사실 3이에요 12살요 3번요
It still works as far as I can tell for everything, but it's not as guaranteed to be compatible.
제가 아는 한 모든 게 잘 작동하지만 호환성이 보장되진 않아요
But still, I'm going to push ahead with this.
그래도 밀어붙일 거예요
Uh, and what we now do is we type Python minus m.
이제 파이썬 마이너스 m을 입력해요
Venv venv.
벵갈루루요
You might wonder what magic, what strange concoction that is.
이게 무슨 마법이고 무슨 이상한 혼합물인지 궁금하실 거예요
Python is saying I want to create a new virtual environment, and then the name of that virtual environment
파이썬 을 보면 새로운 가상 환경을 생성하고 싶다고 합니다 가상 환경의 이름은
is going to be Venv again, which is something that people usually often use.
Venv가 될 것입니다 사람들이 자주 사용하는 것이죠
And if I look in this directory, you'll see that there is now a folder called Venv virtual environment,
이 디렉터리를 보면 Venv 가상 환경이라는 폴더가 있는 게 보이실 겁니다 이
which will contain all of the Python files for this virtual environment.
가상 환경에 대한 모든 파이썬 파일을 갖고 있죠
And so far everything has been the same with a PC.
지금까지는 모든 게 똑같았어요
What I'm going to do now is different between a mac and a PC.
이제 제가 할 것은 Mac과 PC의 차이예요
On a mac, what we're going to do is activate this virtual environment on a mac.
Mac에서 우리가 할 일은 Mac에서 이 가상 환경을 활성화하는 거죠
You do that by typing source venv slash bin slash, activate.
소스 사슴V/ bin/ 활성화라고 입력하면 돼요
And again, all of this is of course I just did that.
이 모든 건 물론 제가 한 거죠
All of this is of course written in the Readme instructions.
물론 이 모든 건 읽기 설명서에 쓰여 있어요
And the way we know we've activated the environment is that Venv appears over here on the left.
환경을 활성화한 방법은 Venv가 여기 왼쪽에 나타난다는 거죠
You can see there's also this base here because I've got Anaconda installed.
여기 이 베이스도 있는 걸 보실 수 있어요 아나콘다가 설치돼 있거든요
You may not see that if you haven't installed Anaconda and on a PC you won't, you won't see that.
아나콘다를 설치하지 않았다면 안 보일 수도 있어요 PC에도요
but that can be safely ignored.
하지만 그건 무시해도 돼요
We are in the venv.
벤트베어에 들어왔어요
Environment.
환경이요
And now what you do, which is something that probably most of you have done many times before, is
이제 여러분이 할 일은 대부분 전에 많이 해보셨을 텐데요 파이썬
we do pip install because we want to install Python packages.
패키지를 설치하기 위해 파이프 설치를 하죠
Minus R means we have a file of names of packages that we want to specify, and it's called requirements.txt.
R은 우리가 명시하길 원하는 패키지 이름의 파일이 있다는 뜻입니다 요구 사항이라고 하죠 txt요
And then when I press enter it is now going to be installing these packages.
엔터를 누르면 이런 패키지들이 설치되고 있어요
But it's not installing them on my the python that comes with my box.
하지만 제 박스에 딸려오는 파이썬에는 설치하지 않아요
It's installing them specifically on this virtual environment called Venv.
Venv라는 가상 환경에 특별히 설치하고 있어요
So I'm isolating my environment from anything else that I might be doing on my computer with Python.
환경을 격리하는 거죠 파이썬 으로 컴퓨터에서 작업하는 다른 것으로부터요
And you can see that there's plenty going on here as it does all of these things.
이 모든 걸 하는 동안 많은 일이 일어나는 걸 볼 수 있죠
It will be slower for you because you can see it's saying it's used cached.
더 느려질 거예요 사용된 캐시라고 하니까요
Because I've done this before, it won't be cached for you presumably.
제가 전에 해봤는데 당신한텐 캐시가 안 되겠죠?
So there'll be a lot of downloading going on, but it's still a lot quicker than setting up the Anaconda,
다운로드가 많이 되겠지만 아나콘다 창을 설정하는 것보다
uh, window.
훨씬 빨라요
And then the business happens at the end.
그리고 사업은 마지막에 일어나죠
Right now it is at the moment, now going ahead and installing all of that.
지금은 모든 걸 설치하고 있어요
And you can see a lot of different packages here.
다양한 패키지가 많이 보이죠
Uh, of course, only some of these are the packages we're actually going to use on this course.
물론 이 중 일부는 이 코스에서 실제로 사용할 패키지들이죠
Many of them are things on which they depend.
많은 부분이 그들이 의존하는 것들이죠
So it's installed both the packages we need and all of their dependencies up there.
필요한 패키지와 종속성 둘 다 설치됐어요
Um, but you'll see that there's things like SQL alchemy, and that's because we're going to be using
SQL 연금술 같은 것도 있어요 그건 우리가 객체 데이터베이스를 사용할
an object database that's going to depend on that.
것이기 때문이죠 그것에 따라 달라져요
Um, and you can see other things going on here.
다른 것들도 볼 수 있어요
Chroma is the the vector data store, a wonderful open source vector data store that we'll be using
크로마는 벡터 데이터 저장소입니다 오픈 소스 벡터 데이터 저장소로 H깅페이스
Tokenizers part of our Huggingface code.
코드의 일부인 토큰라이저를 사용할 거예요
So lots of things you can take your time while it's doing this, to look around and see the names of
이 작업을 하는 동안 시간을 들여 살펴볼 수 있는 게 많아요 우리가 사용할 패키지
some of the packages that we will be using.
이름을 보는 거죠
All right.
좋아요
That has now happened.
그런 일이 벌어졌어요
And it didn't take very long at all.
오래 걸리지 않았어요
And at the end of this, all I have to now do is again, uh oh, I might just quickly mention that the
이 끝에 가서 다시 해야 할 일은 아, 짧게 말씀드릴게요
the command for a PC to activate your environment is in fact venv and then backslash scripts.
환경을 활성화하는 PC 명령은 사실 베니브와 백슬래시 스크립트예요
Backslash activate.
백슬래시 활성화요
So you would type that first and then you would type the pip install r requirements.txt.
그걸 먼저 입력하고 나서 파이프 설치 r 요구 사항을 입력해요 txt요
And of course that's all specified in the readme.
물론 전부 읽기에 명시돼 있죠
But whether you're on a mac or on a PC at this point all you would do is type the simple JupyterLab.
하지만 Mac이든 PC든 이 시점에선 간단한 주피터랩을 입력하겠죠
And with any luck, when I press enter, it is now going to launch the JupyterLab environment.
운이 좋으면 엔터를 누르면 주피터랩 환경이 시작될 거예요
Here it comes.
나오네요
And this is going to be our home for the next few weeks.
앞으로 몇 주간 여기서 지낼 거예요
The next eight weeks.
앞으로 8주요
Folders for each of the eight weeks and the usual setup.
8주간의 폴더와 일반적인 설정이죠
The only difference being now we have this Venv folder which contains our virtual environment.
유일한 차이점은 가상 환경을 포함하는 이 Venv 폴더가 있다는 거죠
So that's the fallback plan.
그게 대비책이에요
I hope that makes sense.
이해가 되셨으면 좋겠네요
If you have any problems at all with the fallback plan, then please, please, please reach out.
만약 대비책에 문제가 있다면 꼭 연락 주세요
I will fix it.
제가 해결할게요
We'll get you on your way quickly.
빠른 배웅 해드릴게요 Get you
All right, on to the next video when we're going to be doing setting up API keys with OpenAI.
좋아요, 다음 비디오로 넘어가 오픈AI로 API 키를 설정하는 걸 알아보죠
See you there.
거기서 봐요